Angelo Gentile III

(201) 523-0880 | angelogentileiii@gmail.com | LinkedIn | Github | Portfolio | IMDB

FULL-STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Full stack software engineer with over nine years of professional experience in the multi-billion dollar film and television industry. Following the completion of an engineering bootcamp, I jumped into a financial technology startup, building ETL pipelines and developing front-end user experiences. I thrive in organizations where I am given space to continue to expand upon my technical knowledge and to openly collaborate with colleagues. I love to blend my creative background with the technical future and I look to maintain a mentorship mindset, to better myself and other engineers within my department..

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript (React, TypeScript, Node.js) | Python (Flask, Pandas, Selenium) | SQL (MySQL, PostgreSQL, SQLite) |
AWS (S3, Lambdas, CloudFormation) | Git/Github Actions | HTML | CSS

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer - Intern

Remote

Point Focal

April 2024 - June 2024

- Developed a financial reporting retrieval system by integrating AWS services and a custom-built Ruby web scraper, providing clients with new business insights and analysis during market's transition to a T+1 time frame
- Designed an event-driven ETL pipeline utilizing AWS S3, Lambda functions, and CloudFormation templates to process SEC failure-to-deliver data, streamlining data ingestion and enhancing operational efficiency
- Engineered GitHub Action workflows to create a seamless deployment process, ensuring efficient integration and delivery of development and production changes, while expanding automated CI/CD pipelines
- Implemented new end-to-end functionality, incorporating Spotfire API integrations, that maintains stylistic uniformity and streamline user experience in the React/TypeScript front-end application

Digital Imaging Technician | Camera Technician

New York, NY

IATSE Local 600

2015 - Present

- Utilized DaVinci Resolve Studio to create custom LUT files for daily production, ensuring consistent color space and exposure alignment across diverse camera systems, while adhering to the production's creative vision
- Leveraged Pomfort Silverstack for MD5 and xxHash-64 checksums during file transfer from camera media to production RAIDs, guaranteeing file security and mitigating opportunities for data corruption
- Designed daily production strategies to optimize the operation of technical camera systems, coordinating with production stakeholders, to provide constructive leadership and effective production workflows

INDEPENDENT PROJECTS

Crew Portal - Github | Demo

A mobile communication platform for film technicians to schedule work and interact with hiring production companies

- Utilized React Native and Node.js/Express.js for app development, ensuring a seamless mobile user experience
- Developed native Apple Calendar integration, enabling seamless event updates and synchronization across user calendars facilitating dynamic scheduling of productions

Red Line Dealership - Github | Demo

An e-commerce web application that allows users to add, save, and purchase vehicles from the dealerships inventory

- Designed a React front-end application using functional components and integrating third-party libraries like React Hooks and Cloudinary API, ensuring a seamless and intuitive user experience
- Developed a Python API with dedicated endpoints optimized for ingesting and accessing product and user data

EDUCATION

Flatiron School New York, NY

Certificate in Full Stack Software Development (Python/Flask and JavaScript/React.js)

2023 - 2024

Emerson College

Boston, MA

Bachelors of Fine Arts in Cinematography (Minors in Photography and Literature)

2011 - 2015